http://www.ijic.org/about/privacy-policy/

Start Submission
Become a Reviewer
Quick links
Privacy PolicyWe take seriously our duty to process your personal data in a fair and transparent way. We collect and manage user data according to the following Privacy Policy. This document is part of our Terms of Service, and by using the press portal, affiliated journals, book, conference and repository websites (the “Websites”), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service. Please read the Terms of Service in their entirety, and refer to those for definitions and contacts.What type of personal data do we handle?There are four main categories of personal data stored by our journal platform, our press platform, and our book management system; Website User data, Author data, Reviewer data and Editor data.The minimum personal data that are stored are:full nameemail addressaffiliation (department, and institution)country of residenceOptionally, the user can provide:salutationgenderassociated URLphone numberfax numberreviewing interestsmailing addressORCiDa short biographyinterestsTwitter profileLinkedIn profileImpactStory profileprofile pictureThe data subjects have complete control of this data through their profile, and can request for it to be removed by contacting info@ubiquitypress.comWhat do we to keep that data secure?We regularly backup our databases, and we use reliable cloud service providers (Amazon, Google Cloud, Linode) to ensure they are kept securely. Backups are regularly rotated and the old data is permanently deleted. We have a clear internal data handling policy, restricting access to the data and backups to key employees only. In case of a data breach, we will report the breach to the affected users, and to the press/journal contacts within 72 hours.How do we use the data?Personal information is only used to deliver the services provided by the publisher. Personal data is not shared externally except for author names, affiliations, emails, and links to ORCiD and social media accounts (if provided) in published articles and books which are displayed as part of the article/book and shared externally to indexes and databases. If a journal operates under open peer review then the reviewer details are published alongside the reviewer details.How we collect and use your data1. When using the website1.1 what data we collectWhen you browse our website, we collect anonymised data about your use of the website; for example, we collect information about which pages you view, which files you download, what browser you are using, and when you were using the site.When you comment on an article or book using Disqus, we are not collecting, controlling or processing the data. More details on the DISQUS privacy policy can be found on their website.When you annotate an article or book, this is done via a 3rd party plugin to the website called Hypothes.is. In using this plugin we are not collecting, controlling or processing the data. More details on the Hypothes.is privacy policy can be found on their website1.2 why we collect the dataWe use anonymised website usage data to monitor traffic, help fix bugs, and see overall patterns that inform future redesigns of the website, and provide reports on how frequently the publications on our site have been accessed from within their IP ranges.1.3 what we do (and don’t do) with the dataWe do not collect personal information that can be used to identify you when you browse the website.We currently use Google Analytics for publication reports, and to improve the website and services through traffic analysis, but no personal identifying data is shared with Google (for example your computer’s IP is anonymised before transmission).1.4 what to do if you want to get a copy of your data, or want your data to be removedPlease contact info@ubiquitypress.com to request a copy of your data, or for your data to be removed/anonymised.2. When registering as an author, and submitting an article or book2.1 what data we collectWhen registering an account we ask you to log in and provide certain personal information (such as your name and email address), and there is the option to register using an ORCiD which will pre-fill the registration form.As part of submitting an article for publication, you will need to provide personally identifying information which will be used for the peer review process, and will be published. This can include ‘Affiliation’, ‘Competing interests’, ‘Acknowledgements’2.2 why we collect the dataRegistering an account allows you to log in, manage your profile, and participate as an author/reviewer/editor. We use cookies and session information to streamline your use of the website (for example in order for you to remain logged-in when you return to a journal). You can block or delete cookies and still be able to use the websites, although if you do you will then need to enter your username and password to login. In order to take advantage of certain features of the websites, you may also choose to provide us with other personal information, such as your ORCiD, but your decision to utilize these features and provide such data will always be voluntary.Personal data submitted with the article or book is collected to allow follow good publication ethics during the review process, and will form part of the official published record in order for the provenance of the work to be established, and for the work to be correctly attributed.2.3 what we do (and don’t do) with the dataWe do not share your personal information with third parties, other than as part of providing the publishing serviceAs a registered author in the system you may be contacted by the journal editor to submit another articleAny books published on the platform are freely available to download from the publisher website in PDF, EPUB and MOBI formats on the publisher’s site.Any personal data accompanying an article or a book (that will have been added by the submitting author) is published alongside it. The published data includes the names, affiliations and email addresses of all authors.Any articles published on the platform are freely available to download from the publisher website in various formats (e.g. PDF, XML)Ubiquity Press books and articles are typeset by SiliconChips and Diacritech.This process involves them receiving the book and book associated metadata and contacting the authors to finalise the layout. Ubiquity Press work with these suppliers to ensure that personal data is only used for the purposes of typesetting and proofing.For physical purchases of books on the platform Ubiquity Press use print on demand services via Lightning Source who are responsible for printing and distribution via retailers. (For example; Amazon, Book Repository, Waterstones). Lightning Source’s privacy policy and details on data handling can be found on their website2.4 why we store the dataWe store the account data so that you may choose to become a reviewer and be able to perform those tasks, or to become an author and submit an article and then track progress of that article.Published personal data that accompanies an article or a book forms part of the official published record in order for the provenance of the work to be established, and for the work to be correctly attributed.2.5 what to do if you want to get a copy of your data, or want your data to be removedYou are able to view, change and remove your data associated with your profile. Should you choose to completely delete your account, please contact us at support@ubiquitypress.com and we will follow up with your request as soon as possible.To conform to publication ethics and best practice any personal data that is published alongside an article or book cannot be removed. If you have a query about a publication to which you are attributed please contact info@ubiquitypress.com3. When registering as a reviewer3.1 what data we collectTo become a reviewer you must first register as a user on the website, and set your preference that you would like to be considered as a reviewer. No new personal data is collected when a registered user elects to become a reviewer.When registering an account we ask you to log in and provide certain personal information (such as your name and email address), and there is the option to register using an ORCiD which will pre-fill the registration form.Reviewers can also be registered by editors who invite them to review a specific article. This requires the editor to provide the reviewer’s First Name, Last Name, and Email address. Normally this will be done as part of the process of inviting you to review the article or book.On submitting a review, the reviewer includes a competing interest statement, they may answer questions about the quality of the article, and they will submit their recommendation.3.2 why we collect the dataThe data entered is used to invite the reviewer to peer review the article or book, and to contact the reviewer during and the review process.If you submit a review then the details of your review, including your recommendation, your responses to any review form, your free-form responses, your competing interests statement, and any cover letter are recorded.3.3 what we do (and don’t do) with the dataThis data is not shared publicly and is only accessible by the Editor and system administrators of that journal or press.The data will only be used in connection with that journal or press.Data that is retained post final decision is kept to conform to publication ethics and best practice, to provide evidence of peer review, and to resolve any disputes relating to the peer review of the article or book.For journals or presses that publish the peer reviews, you will be asked to give consent to your review being published, and a subset of the data you have submitted will become part of the published record.3.4 what to do if you want to get a copy of your data, or want your data to be removedIf you would no longer like to be registered as a reviewer you can edit your profile and  tick the box ‘stop being a reviewer’. This will remove you from the reviewer database, however any existing reviews you may have carried out will remain.If you have been contacted by an editor to peer review an article this means that you have been registered in the system. If you would not like to be contacted for peer review you can reply to the email requesting that your data be deleted.4. when being registered as a co-author4.1 what data we collectCo-author data is entered by the submitting author. The submitting author will already have a user account. According to standard publishing practice, the submitting author is responsible for obtaining the consent of their co-authors to be included (including having their personal data included) in the article/book being submitted to the journal/press.The requested personal data for co-authors are at the bare minimum; first name, last name, institution, country, email address. This can also include; ORCID ID, Title, Middle Name, Biographical Statement, Department, Twitter Handle, Linkedin Profile Name or ImpactStory ID.4.2 why we collect the dataAssuming that it is accepted for publication, this data forms part of the official published record in order for the provenance of the work to be established, and for the work to be correctly attributed.Author names, affiliations and emails are required for publication and will become part of the permanent cited record.4.3 what we do (and don’t do) with the dataThe co-author’s personal data is stored in the author database. This personal data is only used in relation to the publication of the associated article.Any co-author data collected is added to the author database and is only used in association with the article the user is co-author on.4.5 what to do if you want to get a copy of your data, or want your data to be removedTo receive a copy of your data, please contact info@ubiquitypress.comTo conform to publication ethics and best practice any personal data that is published alongside an article or book cannot be removed. If you have a query about a publication to which you are attributed please contact info@ubiquitypress.com5. when signing-up to receive newsletters5.1 what data we collectWe require you to include your name and email address5.2 why we collect and store the data, and for how longThis data would be collected to keep you updated with any news about the platform or specific journal5.3 what we do (and don’t do) with the dataWe use mailchimp to provide our mailing list services. Their privacy policy can be found here5.4 what to do if you want to get a copy of your data or want your data to be removedAll emails sent via our newsletter client will include a link that will allow you to unsubscribe from the mailing listNotification about change of ownership or control of dataWe may choose to buy or sell assets. In the case that control of data changes to or from Ubiquity Press and a third party, or in the case of change of ownership of Ubiquity Press or of part of the business where the control of personal data is transferred, we will do our best to inform all affected users and present the options. (Updated: 18 May 2018)
E-ISSN: 1568-4156
Published by Ubiquity Press
Terms and Conditions
Privacy Policy
